Welcome,
welcome, welcome...has pop-up...redoing.
Good...more people answered expected answered at five o'clock in the day so thank you
very much for coming my name is average hooper ame technically managers
...microsoft working out of southern california I do a lot on the gaming side I came
from enterprise background and about two years ago by accident somebody hack upon mentioned something about unity
who knows about the dependency injection software unity right and that's what I thought they were talking about and I found
...whole game engine out there and that change my career so things happen
...crazy way here don't forget the some evaluation that's important to all...especially myself?
We're going to be doing and overview of unity how many people are using unity currently you folks
third folks article...to do it...overview this is not can be an
...session although for the folks...uni
...a couple basing points and asher not totally lost looking at the interface and what we're doing
tooling where microsoft fits in on a tooling story with unity?
And, universal windows apps and universal windows platform talk about how we can build for that from unity
...some cross device strategies and where we're going a little bit of a roadmap?
So, unity and visual studio my two favorite software products.
...five is the recent version where they may some really cool announcements outside
...support they change the licensing model on there so if you get the free version or the pro
version they have the same basic feature set ninety nine-point nine inine the same feature set
pro gives you some additional cloud-based services analytics build et-cetera so,
my favorite features I'll just talk about real quick here animation if you have any sort of character
...for example, let's say you have the zombie that...bought
...which I'll talk about or designer created for you can take any animation maybe somebody shooting
and aero or somebody doing zombie walk where I've seen one literally in...game I saw...doing
...them style dance you can take those animations and apply them to any other character and
...animations the graphics engine was revamping...changes their to give essentially triple a
quality highlighting and your games optimizing they've got a profiler
built-in unity as well as a framed bagger now as well as the audio system
unity was also revamping five and now they have a audio mixer and tutti
and three-d physics they use to very well-known engines out there and, there are other products
...as well box tutti and in...and video physics...that allows you
to have hundreds of physics objects in your scenes things bouncing around
cloudy with each other so very high-performance...five things you couldn't do in the
prior for versions and from scripting standpoint support csharp and that's all I care about.
The first image here's an example you can see...aaa quality demo they put out there that characters
...animation system the second time the global illumination system gi that's including now
and unity five the third screen shot there is from the profiler you want to look at
the memory analysis and...call things like that you can all do that
...unity and lastly...two-d tools which will look at a little bit later on as well.
Is unity right for you and there's one reason I show this slide
...has a forty five percent market share the next
...competitor seventeen percent and I want to be a
sales I'm I want to be from developer standpoint I develop something I...support
...for there's a large community using a particular product a our millions
...developers using uni and almost any question you ask to find...a very stack overflowed type format
or forums and our people info download etc...almost any question you can go
and search on...somebody's already ask before and if not there's a great community help you out?
All right let's get right into a demo.
And, let's not be and presenter mode let's go and duplicate my screen.
Do jumping jacks and you can see it?
Hi, yes, anything anybody was going to thank you.
All right so this...what we're going to create...how we can kind of...and together before we do other things like
...into platform so this is a fun game idea to start a fairly recently called
metal warfare.
I have...for that.
So, this is...warfare your tank.
Driver tank and you can do fun things like
...the around and...this stuff.
Because that's what really happens in real-life.
Samoa.
You get the idea there's a timer counting down you have two minutes or its doom and a little
...counter it's a fairly.
Decent looking game although from a standpoint is actually fairly simple.
And, it might look like...complex so what kind of kind...deconstruct this a little bit
and see how we can actually build this up so do that let's start with another instance of humanly have open
here I'll just show you kind of steps I...get here and just...file new project.
My...demo you may supports to dem three-d is a three-d engines so even
...two games are really three-d environment is just fixing...to axis wire developing
...pop in and out of that so it's very easy to make a two-point-five the game,
for example, where you mix three-d...missing?
...my...on my demo.
Create project but before we do that there's also this box here and when I first arguing
development want to check everything off...I...they did and don't do that
...thought the only the same...these think of them is a new get packages in a senses
...package functionality you can bring your game some?
Get install my...default right there and you can...from anywhere if you download stuff...the access or will show you
...shortly those come down as...packages I have a folder I keep all my favorite
unique packages and they're just essentially compress files lots of functionality can be audio
scripts images three-d models all package japanese
...little bundles so just for this one's to show you how we started building it...
check-off environment and the environment package brings in some things like trees usually five now use this
been tree system awesome tree system also use in movies and
...some images I can use the kind of texture...little bit and that's all I did but just
to save time I will cancel that out and...show you?
The next step out of there.
Now...interface again this is intrude unity...do want to kinda talk about the interface or some folks
argue...here this is your virtual environment here this is
...level this is your...is we're going to your design...of unity.
Think
about work on a form like an example designer something everything here this is what's in your scene.
And, over here on the properties what's
you're seeing now everything ninety nine-point nine percent of everything stems
...game object just like...is not object net right ninety nine-point
you say that again for third-time they...nine percent of things in dot net I'm here from system the
object think about game object as a root object for almost everything else it has a basic naming
has a tag just like in visual studio or when you're doing windows former...development...tags something
is...texturing...can use...describe something we can find something my tag?
So, name a tag and transform where'd isn't space.
You can move things around...equates to these buttons
...toolbar as well now everything else after that are components everything comes to life
by components if I look at a light is nothing more than a game object
that these properties and got this like component on top of their if I look at
the camera is also a game object has a camera components what turns
new camera when you add a script gets added as a component two-game object if I look at
...for example, a cuba's a game object
...got a mesh filter which is responsible for reading the vertices...the model and passing out over to this thing called
...measure under which makes it visible or invisible your see the...games we have this invisible border the
...me like I wonder how...that.
Invisible mortar that's exactly what happens.
...so let's look at some of the built-in functional
...is not a three-d modeling system asterisks because they do have some tools built-in you can
do some three-d modeling and there's third-party tools like...for example,
we can actually do modeling inside unity but...one of the built-in systems here since I use it to build-out that
...game and that's the terrain...
...a new terrain and comes out is...here I want to textured I want to add image on
to that terrain and that's what this paintbrush here's for so I...my train I get
...components a game object with some other components
here and I click on the paintbrush.
I can add...texture in other words I can take an image in plastered all over there so I'm going to add a texture here and...
And, if I search for ground or grass there's a couple basic ones...
First one gets applied goes all over the entire surface so you can
see it's repeatable how do you change that a real-world environment
when we solve this game right here if you get close sometimes some things look repeatable by
mixing it up by...different textures on top of you can see here about some sand there's a...texture there's
...little...the green texture so my randomized in your terrain things look a little bit different.
Now we need to...this out that's nothing we can do with our
...tools here the first one raise or lower terrain and I think this is like my favorite
...because you can do cool things like this.
Start drawing stuff out.
If you
want paint something like a plateau or mesa specific.
Was a little high.
Windows up you can actually use notes...come in any road them down a little bit more
...of some of these are very like a very jagged not realistic looking so can
...down a little bit more and as you can race so can-you shrink
one little pathway from a...to run through their...canyon valley make a little randomized
also straight and just like that we have a basic terrain of course I would want to take other images
in plaster on there but that's how you stop
...take a bunch of images plastered on top of their and painted and
...could add one or more detectors under the...
The next thing I did was brought
...couple trees and again usually uses the speech tree system so if we search
...trees...environment packed we broaden gives us a couple trees.
those and I can...a big area but let's be sparing.
From california there's not much
...from california some to be a little sparing these trees here.
You guys are like are what happens to be...click an area.
That's what happens or my favorite button of all time mass place trees
...give thousand trees there we go so just like that we can do
grass we can paint rocks on...we can do all these other different textures.
Those are built-in tools newly we saw the game we actually had more than just that involved
so that kind of brought me over to the...store I was...architecture many years before joining microsoft
and I can draw means stick figure and that's about it so if I want to create a game
...somewhat cool then I go ahead and grab stuff...store I know
couple designers but most of what I use I...store and I think that's what makes usually
...of the most powerful marketplaces I work a lot of game deb so on any
...development...shops and near everybody I talk to use a something from the
...or they might not use a zombie from...store they might use scripts that...extend
...interface but we can grab you want three-d model here game you want free three-d models
or...models here's a whole bunch of free ones listed there zombie female character
...download...can use them insider game without any kind of world
...the free ones are free to pay...you download and using...done.
...audio for your game perfect free audio pay audio very high-quality assets
on so in making out ...warfare the...game I showed you
the beginning I grab a couple packs of the as a store I guess audio aggravating...action
...helicopter...I grab a middle east
...on there and that romy over to this.
So, I took that terrain.
And, just kind of changed a little bit abroad some...can kind of see here took
a couple different images...that up but now the magic happens in the rest of it so we have
a basic terrain here some concrete on side of their.
Next was taking.
Some of these prefabricated,
prefabricated objects that you can just take...you're seeing you can make your improve abs and
unity literally you take something from here and you dragging down there...becomes prefabricated you can reuse it across
...these prefabricated that this designer said hey I want to give you reusable bits of information so these
...prefabricated and if we want...iraq, for example,
take a...there of course stacking as up side-by-side look a little bit goofy
so it's all about randomized placing environment
randomized anything's scaling up scaling down a little bit.
Randomized...so...there we take.
...hangar.
Couple guard towers...focus look at those look all right and it's all about just taken kind
of the minute details...we can dragged big things around what about little things...fence, for example,
framenet.
So, you...the idea take objects snap together.
Make these environment's that's about what it looks like there.
The next step on there who was taking one of the other...I got.
Prefabricated equals.
...be clear I did write a little bit of code run I didn't quite like the way the operated this physics
...so I want to change the functionality it was the first-person I one of the bagel ai
into it...make a little...code changes on there.
But, it did work out-of-the-box so.
You can see how this level here actually looks pretty similar to the one that I showed you beginning here.
That's what we've got our tank there.
We've got a helicopter also but as a pack.
I got a script that actually will piece apart your matches and read-only versus industry that when you
...whether...do...so using all the powerfully asked our kind of create
a game here and ...designer to do a little bit of work which I'll talk about just a tiny bit here.
So, we've got this game.
Let's talk about some of the tooling that we have
to make things a little bit easier for the game developer for somebody using unity here.
We purchased...a company called syntax tree within the last year and they had a product
called unity vs and was to
use unity with visual studio and was about a hundred plug-in that you
...unity I know a lot of folks that love...they...it but also cost a hundred bucks so we bought them and we
turn-around we made this product free.
And, this allows you use visual studio to edit debug code the fall
is model develop and we use visual studio...probably...and most people.
So, this allows you use visual studio to not only edit but also to debug your coding
...will look at surely this makes...to integrate together pretty seamlessly.
This gives you shaver syntax highlighting intel sense like you'd expect
...id...code template...my favorite features of that and
...debugging support with unity you can use any text...want you just can't
debug your code out-of-the-box works among developed this allows you now you visual studio to debug your code.
So, what happens...plug-in...installing visual studio you
...package into your game and two-one uses the existing
...that model develop uses to talk back and forth there's a soft debug that
...uses and allows you talk back and forth between visual
studio use the same underlying mechanism that...developed...as well?
Anybody here about this.
The partnership for tools...work with unity
and visual studio community addition is going to be an option during install,
install for unity and some other tools as well where during
setup click quick...visual studio community addition as your...going to work very seamlessly
...well you can use model developers wealthy...but I'm a visual studio get.
All right let's look at what that looks like.
...the partnership happen because I think this is one of the cools tools.
You can look for visual studio tools...st you folks call it you can also go to
...tvs dot com select...version that you want.
Easy that downloads installs in your system...visual studio
for you installs and asset package like us talk about earlier unity package that
you can see so let's look at what that looks like let's take this basic one that we did before.
And, under assets import package we can always
bringing those little check boxes that I show you the beginning that new project...we always bring
...later at any time we can either use these we can double-click on one our system we don't have
to uses I just...see that the visual studio tools freely installs here
...listed as visual studio twenty fifteen tools click on that
...tells you a this is what inside let-you package file and there's just these two libraries
...import that.
That's it done.
And, you menu peers up here generate project file you typically don't have to click that this
...runs just automatic but I'll show you another change
the happens here inside of you need want to changer...center or see...code
...edit preferences external tools.
And, default is model developed as soon as you install this tooling...to this file opener...open file.
Let's go ahead and create a csharp script here.
We will make let's making evil cube.
So, I'm a...class called q comptroller very important to make sure that your
filename matches your classroom otherwise things will work.
Double-click on it visual studio opens up.
Ogg there's my new and
...usually gives you a new class with two methods
...your to very common methods is probably about seven that use on occasion maybe even less
...you start and update stark it's called...to starting up.
Updates called...reframe let's add something more into here.
One of the things that I love...use all-time
with visual studio tools for unity is trying to remember what knees methods argument if I know I
...detect collision between two objects I know there's an on collision enter theirs on trigger enter
...that...and trigger...on trigger enter
...deep itu-t object of collision or to the if is to
...object and methods...time there's different parameters the past and I'm trying
...api...sometimes a little difficult so control shift m
brings you up these helpers that are installed by the st you and this gives you all the common
...methods that you would use and will generate those methods stubs for you so,
for example,to...collider so I can
see on collision internet two-d on collision...right there?
Go ahead and insert that.
And, here we have it right there
...on collision enter the reset my size here for some reason my
...control seems to be stuck here there we go.
So, let's say if this particular game object...code is assigned two-game object.
If who we've just collided with.
Collision dogging object that we get a intel sensor for usually properties
...objects.
So, if we've collided with the player that's go ahead and just destroy yourself.
Destroyed this game object in two seconds.
And, we'll...point there so we're very used to this process notice we
don't have to worry about this...debug release this is
...we used to seeing something like debug and.
We can...and emulator and all sorts of stuff there right now we have...usually attaching play.
So, if we want to debug this we just click that.
I'll show you that one second we need...more background work here I'm saying by colliding the player
destroyed what we have...assigned this code...let's do a real basic example here and
...create a game object...cubed.
...put that one.
Will duplicate that cubed and move this guy up so we're going to...them?
In order to fall we need to given object a rigid body component
using unity you're very familiar that you...object
mass and gravity you simply give it rigid body and we'll see it fall now the codes
...yet...that's go ahead and take that code.
Give that to our...
And, let's make the.
Top cube the player just a tag assist a string were signing to it.
All right that's go ahead and debug code attached unity.
All right we come over here and that's go ahead and play.
Boom soon as the object collided we get thrown the
visual studio unity is actually hung up right now because it's we're in the middle
debug call right now so if we want to continue this we can just either...continue
...cc and all the same debugging exist here if you want to do if...want to see all your watches.
If you want all the helpers here it all works as you'd expect work inside
a visual studio so this is extremely useful will say continue.
After two seconds ago destroys itself.
The other thing that the visual studio tools really gives you.
Is...syntax highlighting?
So, just let-me easy on the eyes of your writing...a custom...just to get the syntax highlighting
...there so another nice little feature there.
When you're done you just click stop you don't have to detachment process...not going to kill
...just click stop-and-go you're all done?
All right so that was cool...unity and the next thing we have
our diagnostics and you can use the visual
studio graphics debugging for diagnostics gives you some really low-level information...typically want to
...when things are displaying right need to get the bottom of what's going on.
This has foley only support.
And, this will give you the ability capture one or multiple frames low-level debugging
...will take a will look...little example of this but very important point this
requires visual studio twenty thirteen cp five or above
...it won't work with unity so fully support...make sure you have the right version to be able to support that.
And, this get ready to demo.
I have a build that I created the...we'll...look at the end it's
...cart before the horse a little bit I have a build a
...games I want to show you the graphics tools here.
And,...I want to do for this.
Is show you the various options first we can under the debug graphics menu...studio
debug install that package so any applications that you have installed locally under
system you can debug those if I bring up that list here?
You'll see all the difference store...packages installed...the system.
And, you have...couple different options...script only native only if you only one look at the gpu or mixed
manager native then you could start debugging on that.
But, actually have a build here
...warfare so we're going to look at that and...go debug.
Graphics start diagnostics.
...launched.
Siesta that.
Let's try to get it right when I...
I'm going to shoot and use my...to touch-screen can just touch-screen the same time here.
...called that.
Now of word of warning here.
I was doing debugging I thought only captured couple frames...look at the information
behind-the-scene and seven gigs of data captured so you get a...lot of data for
the low-level diagnostics so...be careful about how long you're going to be doing captures for.
You can capture again as I said one or multiple frames actually have a project...did with a good capture on
...your same thing that were why is the point of impact on that barracks
their?
On...I should say and you can get all the list of all
...calls here.
So, one of things annealing performance on games everything is drawn-out many times the second and the more
drawl calls that you have per frame issued the slower that
your game is likely going to run and per eavesdrop call you can look at some really low-level information
...with the...was source code...etc but you can also come here and see.
That scrolls down a little bit here.
If I see that something looks a little bit weird on a particular object my
...have a pink object coming up...can happen if you have...issues or if you just want
to see how you're seeing is being composed click on a particular pixel and for any pixel
...so let's select something here from might my high-level one element.
And, you see...history here for that single pixel on your screen gives
...value tells you the initial color here.
What happened on this first one here so that pixel got written out is
...generic sky there with...blue color and...points I'm after that
...call four three four two that's not in a...number...not forty...culture?
Now you can see the difference between two of them I have no...know-how
...there are very xone drew that image on top of their and you can see it's actual value
their and down below you can see...the...and what
...that particular element here...just that particular element drawn-out?
And, you can even more information that so just kind of a quasi high-level view of the information get
with that graphics debug...very easy to launch and very powerful.
Any captures lot-of information more information that you could ever
...or maybe one maybe that hard-core all right let's go back to.
...graphics debugged yet.
Couple folks are using selling...of data.
...recap every usually addition can use visual service of your visual studio I'm sorry
...for on unity five and free or professional you can use visual studio
tools for unity and visual student community addition or bob so we have a retail version visual
sari works fine if you're using visual studio expressed
...upgrade that to a visual studio community addition control shift...the visual studio tools
really I think is one of the best things because I was...method signatures that gives you all the
...list...can just click one it gives you the...generates at code free
...biographer low-level diagnostics low-level information unity actually has a
...version five may have a frame-level
debug sort of say built-in unity the visual studio one who gives you so much cool information?
Our...talk about the universal windows platform or, you know, bp the you
...probably heard a hundred and eighty seven times today.
How do you go from your gain to all...different devices this
idea of this universal platform running on everything in the world?
How do you take a game and deliver...you got phone found...with large numbers
...classic laptops desktop all-in-one
...and xbox service ub and more to come I'm sure that aren't listed on there there's probably going
to be who knows...crazy stuff ballard
movie screen displays probably the process is actually pretty simple to taker game over there?
And, you start with unity of course and...will intern
...compiled project as a visual studio solution you
...of the visual studio solution and then you intern do something with
...solution the...processes pretty easy so let's go ahead and look at that.
Inside...unity so I've got my complete...here this is one that ran just like this.
Like here and I can and...starting.
So, I'm going to build settings who knows the build short-cut in visual studio of the same one which makes it really,
really handy for...like shortcuts a control shifty.
And,...here we need a scene so
...there's a game that we're working on we have think forty different seen files
are projectsome test...to test...I want...going my file project
...and this one I only want this particular one scene you can either drag-and-drop...
...multiple ones...I'm...current scene in there.
And, we're going to build for windows store now previously if you look at...usually that you'll have access to
currently you'll see there's windows store in there and we can target windows
...windows eight one we can target phoning one
...universally one of course you can see kind of the
...going this like this like this like this to this one stored as one platform and you'll
see here pretend for a moment the asa w and this actually says uw p.
Universal windows platform.
You have to from project types you can selectors
...direct three-d I like csharp...choose...here.
And, this other one is also pretty cool.
Usually csharp projects.
When you do...from here to generate your visual studio solution...will take all the or source code
...have inside immunity and...those up
...separate project for those and...references your final game you can actually go
...debug your code and one of the things that we've been working together with unity as you can actually
...the middle studio close unity going-to visual studio say you know,
what I don't like a lot of code I can make a change
...visual studio it actually calls back off to unity to recompile it with certain exceptions you can't
make huge amount of...reliable changes your class I can make certain code changes
...all just come back and work without having to go through the whole...again?
Some to build this...new folder call-in demo
There we go to
build my acid my scene post-processing they do a lot of work behind-the-scenes take all this stuff up and
...so it just works you're not going to get access to all the low-level
unity engine, for example.
...can see the source code for every single thing going on there the
packaged up nicely into the solution let's run that middle warfare.
There are couple things to be aware of while that's loading let me come back here and
...the player settings you have a couple different waves specifying the details
...get pushed down to your package
...app x manifest file so that's the settings as your capabilities tells what
...image assets are the your splash screen your icon your wide icon you...on your small
...kind of...specified in your package...epics manifest file now you can go
...visual studio side and set those if you want or you can do it on the side and that's what all these
ifor right here...splashing image.
...to set the various icons you can do here and all that does is it pushes it down
a visual studio project the first-time you build it repeated builds will not overwrite...so just a word of
caution that if you come and change it and build again unless you lita folder one...
So, there are builds.
Here we have it.
There's a couple options here.
Arm and x eighty-six notice this project open up by default with arm
...running alarm system here I'm running on x eighty-six base system...change over the x
eighty-six.
When I choose arm if I'm going to deploy out to a...when I would be choosing...
Debug...now think about in visual studio typically for done
...project semi...settings we have we have...configurations I should say
...types right we have debug and released releases production ship it and
...optimized well now we have three-four
uni projects and each server good purpose and debug is of course not optimized the supports the
...profiler and optimized the next level up is release releases in the middle
...on this one and releases is optimized but also
supporting these profiler and master is a fully
optimize doesn't support the profiler that's the building it shipped out that's on the
can-you customers as one that you can ideally able to store fully optimized no profiler support.
Master when you're dealing with universal windows apps that's going to as its last
...do a dot net native compilation there so process as a rightnow on the bits I have to
take a little bit so I'm going to show you...a release build today again remember less that middle build.
While that's compiling you see over here this data folder.
That is what...overwrite every time so repeat bills community and pushing
...middle studio just...their own data folder.
...custom source code there...my own...purchases and...native code there I can do that way
...so I've got my game.
It's running actually pretty good.
And, this one here again cool.
Scales the defaults.
Apps for your universal windows apps they will open up in a
...environment like this which to me I think...looks better specially from games...point here.
Just keep in mind that users can do this they can come here and resize the applications
...scale...so keep this...and...such a...shortly.
Okay, cool.
So, that's the point...local machine now if you are.
In the mood two-run things slowly you can run your game inside...I don't recommend
...now is recommend testing on as much physical hardware...can...out to a phone, for example,
you switch...change the arm can run it and deploys...to your windows...
You can run the simulator remember the simulators...and emulator
...a simulator so-if want to check out different pixel density displays you want to fake a...display
...game looks...that side of the simulator you can test out some of this inside of unity
...look at that kind of the next section we talk about the ui but really it's really,
really, really important...on different display sizes
...simulator scale things out we're working on a game once and there's a
softer the actual take screen shots running all these different resolutions and what I thought...my system works on
my machine and looked awful...about ninety...the resolution so definitely test set?
So, thinking about other devices here talking about phone and...desktop.
We have to consider crossed my strategies there's.
A couple different ways to do this but we are...error now work you want to
take one build...you can take one build and run it on a variety devices from
development standpoint sometimes it's a lot easier to do that and have to do...build here seven build their
...separate build there?
The first thing
...to look at is designing for different screens and there's tooling as built...of...that can help you
...so multiple resolutions...aspect ratios different device
capabilities...run across the screen...sizing so we ran the games
domingo saw that I took that window and dragnet expect users are not going to run
...necessarily fix aspect ratio they're going to run...full-screen my window it that's up to the user
to control so we can use a couple things don't...for this right now and we're working with them and integrating ongoing for
...techniques here so unity
ui which I'll show you a demo in a second is one way of doing this formally call-you gooey favor her
...you do is now called unity ui user interface another technique you can use
are called asset bundles as a...require a little bit more work to...but if you have,
for example, a high-definition tank...the xbox and...low definition
...uoneon mobile, for example, you basically sign them to different avce acid bundles
...fone and then at runtime you upload you pulled...of the internet
...source and the
...built me unity to logos packages up such one
technique doing that another one is a using a...cessna target
multi-stream layouts so let's look at what I did hear for middle warfare.
So, there's kind of the basic hub heads up display...was design there.
That's coming to level here that doesn't have a basically duplicate that one took it back out.
I talk to designer and I said hey work attain game what is your
also artistic vision because I can do stick figures you better than me so what can you come up with...said
...has like that that's great so much better and I can do so...the asses for that all
the samper ones and I brought them into my project for here.
If I want to take this guy in
...my...you know,...doesn't work quite like that there's this two-d...unity.
And, underneath our game object menu ui we can create all these different elements that we've been able to make the
comparison visual studio right panel buttons texts images slider scroll bar so
all these different components you would think of these different ui elements you can do a lot of these
inside of unity and credo custom one this system is an open-source system you can find code for eliminate.
So, let's go ahead and do and image now clearly that's not what I want because I look at
that images plastered great...display ship it
...that's not what I want...on that particular image
...take that top left image bringing over here and drop that guy on there?
preserve aspect ratio because that's not what I want their presume aspect ratio.
So, the thing I can do if you notice this box
running my screen here this is representative of the current screen
on notice as I change my window size.
That changes so think of that is the boxes going to define the resolution
a size the aspect ratio of whatever system you're running on whether
to phone or like this system so this is a good way to test it out you can actually scale here and see how
...changes so I bring this guy at the top left this is my top left-hand element and I
go to my game tab here to see what would look like based on...first frame.
As I start scaling notice that's not what I want the same disappears
...see what's happening here if I go to the side.
Is actually just getting pushed off that's because it's
anchor point in the center the screen so everything is doing is relative to that point is
...and fixed over there you move over I'm going to stay fix
to that and just like we can visual studio can...different ui elements around we knew the same thing
...of unity and that's what this guy's for overhear rather than a transform
...to the...have a...to transform object and on a...transform this little drop down we
get docking options that kind of remind me of what I would do with...inside
...visual studio?
So, I want to...to the top left this will move it to the top left and
encrypt for me so I can...shift and alt.
With the top left...can see that might anchor point is now up there.
So, if I look at my game and...out.
You can see that image stays the same size
it's not getting smaller but it's also not getting pushed off the silo screen anymore.
So, easy way to handle at is I take my anger point which is actually for points they look
bundle up there...a one and I can just bring them around the edge of my object like that.
And, now I'm saying...anchoring these for corners.
Essentially pinning it there and that's going to be relative to harm
...screen...notice as I get smaller
...scale smaller I can do the same thing with text boxes on there sometimes I
want default anchoring positions so that top middle one that we did here.
Let's take signal image here
came object ui image and given that top middle.
Set the aspect ratio
...this to top middle well just so happens that because it's in the top middle there.
And,...anchors right there...of like that works all right.
Now of course it's not changing size so I'd
probably one of bring this out here the edges.
at the edge again you can do this will...you get the idea is just to elements here.
Fully scales out so the easiest way to deal with multi device resolution...your objects test it
...some helpers right here and, there's some pretty cool stuff available nearly access tours well
...actually said a whole bunch of these for you take screen shots for you at all different
...show you a gallery this is what it looks like across fifty devices you contestants...aspect ratio
...I can see
what it looks like on a sixteen by nine or for my three.
And, you can add your on...you're working with particle device...want to add your own resolution on their
...aspect ratio you can do as well very easy setup.
Our next sharing code.
When you have platform specific code that you want to run this way
...one platform and this way...different platform you can use
preset processor directives inside of...and there's a whole bunch of that are
built in this one would say if I'm building for unity...here so
...ap imagine for me days and w that uw p so for building currently for
uw p and I'm not running...these editor then go ahead andcompiled a bit of
We can take a step further you'll see that very common inside...projects
...will target all different platforms I want you...that purchases on ios here using that I
want to android over here...windows over here so this is very common
...type of code inside immunity another thing you can do is you can write plugins you can do this before they change
...plug-in model...five and I'll show you that in one second here
but from a high-level standpoint here you have to libraries you have one that
has your functionality built into it that has your api that's going to be used when unity
bills your visual studio project...that guy and when you are running...unity is an
environment a virtual environment that runs model mono not dot
net for windows store different requirements different api so you need to say that
hey we're compiling for...to store I want to use this library and when you running inside
these editor you're going to use this stub library that has, you know, some fake function calls
...or word our we want to act communities editor that's a second library...libraries?
And, inside...itself you have settings and basically say hey we compile
use this library and when you're running the editor use this one let's look at what that actually looks like here?
This is a real basic example I
have to products and generated one I did a file new
projects and all-new project specified this was a windows universal
classed library so it's going to understand that code and that name space.
And, compile a particular way again that does not work
...unique runs on a particular version model inside
...a little virtual environment secondly I have a
...library and this particular library here.
If we look at this is
a dot net framework three to five so that has the same api compatibility with what's running inside of
...editor this is my stun library this is what I have my the code that's going to fix something out
...do I think it out real easy way of doing this
is you share your code between these projects if you've ever seen this if I say ad.
And, I point-two a csharp file.
If you're not familiar with this ad is link you add a source code project a file
...project but it doesn't copy...your project just links to somewhere else there's any
when the numbers and you'll see this extensively throughout the...source code...actually first-place...you add is a link
and the cool thing that happens is when I compile here for my windows universal library?
This is true.
How do I know it's true what easy enough I just look at my properties?
I can see our here's my conditional compilation
...core...windows you ap.
So, I know that's true so I compile this is going to work.
And, I'm asking...new...particular contract present.
Universal window apps operate on this
idea of contracts hey is this contract present on the system and asking for that is a
...you support this phone contract what this other stuff library running side of these
...editor has no idea what that is so if I look at that code.
...see the icons a little bit different here is the link csharp file.
This is no longer true this project...know anything about it so
when I compile...that out so I take those two libraries and drag
...over the unity and insider unity here I go to plugins.
And, in the new system you can put a bunch of different locations I just like to have a...folder because I'm old-school.
And, I highlight library does drag-and-drop and here platform tools...ll and I can specify
hey this particular version is going to
use only when you compile for windows store apps.
Or...is the stub library and you're going to use this with somebody comes in the
...click play.
See specify which platform you want to be used for annually will smartly pull
...in at the time when it needs any source code changes you make behind-the-scene usually
will compile for-you automatically so when you click on play right here...is already
...source code and compiled it's not a manual step it just happens automatically so the
same principle happens here you check these often this just happens automatically.
Our next a high-level...we go how
The...you're seeing now is going to be targeted in unity five dot to
...not out yet ...working hard making...available in the coming months.
Remember that unity pro licenses so,
free and pro from a software feature set are basically the same
levels each other usually pro you get these additional cloud services analytics...but you also get access
to beta versions when they become availablethis was not available yet working hard to make is available the coming months?
Masking target windows ten with
rone store that store is going to have marius device families and
...be able to target everything you can be able to target mobile desktop.
Xbox you...target all one package or multiple packages as the same...so the
options going-to be there for you as a developer to do it however you want to target one or individual.
What else runs windows ten?
How...know-how answer?
This is cool because there is currently this was announce on use...morning so this is public information
now announcing support for microsoft
...there is going to be a unity sdk
...team is working very hard very awesome on...to integrate right with unity you can be able to
some really cool stuff from usually deploying...so stay tuned for information on that.
...windows ten games are
never let universal windows platform and universal windows apps they allow
a single package they are single package you can target one...can target
...up...developer the bits are going to look for coming and we find out to write your game
...that you doing testing using all those different resolutions go...visual gone the visual studio
running a simulator run on different devices I like unity even before gets
there and just change my...ratios said all up inside unity so it looks like it's a real quick way to test
it out platform specific code you can use plug-in is not a difficult process we just saw it
you have to libraries...stub...not and they just share file between
in compile that...call that from within...csharp files super easy and please take advantage of the other tool
we put out there microsoft visual studio community addition visual studio tools
...really create a cool experience running inside immunity.
Thank you very much they...second first...and resources.
And, tomorrow morning I will be...tonight from I think sixty-eight we've been doing the expert zone and I think
tomorrow morning to working over the insiders area so if you have any questions you...development
relation advice anything...come over and visit me over there and I thank you very much and enjoy the rest of your build.